James M. Hale IT INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER

2630 Adams Mill Rd NW, Apt 207 Washington, D.C. 20009

413-896-7607 jmhale08@gmail.com jmhale@protonmail.com

Profile

Senior-level infrastructure engineer with more than six years of experience, specializing in architecting and deploying secure, scalable, and highly-available systems, using cloud-based and on-premises infrastructure resources, including hybrid solutions. Specialties include: AWS, VMware, networking, and automation.

Education and Certifications

University of Massachusetts Amherst - B.S. Computer Science, 2009 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate - License AWS-ASA-10580

Relevant Skills

Languages:	Python, Go, Ruby, Java, PHP, Perl, YAML, and JSON
Configuration Management:	Puppet, SaltStack, Ansible, and Chef
IaaS Platforms:	AWS, VMware, Google Compute Engine, and OpenStack
Database technologies:	NoSQL: MongoDB, DynamoDB, and Redis. RDS: MySQL, PostgreSQL, and AWS Aurora
Containerization technologies:	Docker and LXC

- Primarily focused on deploying fault-tolerant, highly-available, and secure systems across a multitude of platforms
- Expertise with cloud and on-premises infrastructure platforms, IaaS/PaaS, including designing and implementing hybrid solutions.
- Strive to provide infrastructure as a service to software developers and facilitate their deployment tasks
- Experience with automating system deployment and administration tasks using configuration management platforms.
- Knowledge of Datacenter/NOC operations
- Experience with various NAS and SAN storage systems

Work Experience

The Washington Post, Washington, D.C.

Senior Infrastructure Engineer, January 2015 – present

• Implement ephemeral, long-lived and immutable infrastructure as code, using AWS CloudFormation

- and internally-built solutions
- Maintain infrastructure resources in an auditable and repeatable fashion using configuration management platforms and version control systems
- Responsible for designing and implementing robust network and security architectures
- Help to maintain a strong information security posture for data in transit and data at rest
- Provide expertise to software developers on AWS services and best practices, such as EC2 (incl. EBS, ASG, ELB), VPC/Direct Connect, Route53, S3, IAM/KMS, RDS, SNS, SQS, SES, and CloudWatch
- Contribute to internal software projects, centered around the orchestration of infrastructure resources and the continuous deployment of containerized applications to test and production environments

Unix Systems Engineer, December 2011 – January 2015

- Managed physical and cloud-based infrastructure for the print, mobile, and web properties of Washington Post Media
- Supported content management systems and applications utilizing Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, and dynamic Java applications deployed on Glassfish or WebLogic application servers.
- Maintained Unix production, stage, and test environments, utilizing RedHat 5/6/7, CentOS 5/6/7, Solaris 9 & 10, AIX 5.3, HP-UX and Mac OS X Server
- Performed code deployments for development teams
- Carried out system maintenance and upgrades as needed, including backups and restorations
- Participated in 24x7 on-call rotation
- Assisted with a major datacenter relocation

Client Systems Engineer, September 2010 – December 2011

- Developed and maintained Windows and Mac desktop images, software deployments, and application patching while also identifying and resolving desktop security issues.
- Provided technical expertise to assist with implementation of desktop technologies: Windows and Mac
 desktops and laptops and their operating systems, desktop applications, management systems, and
 tools
- Created and supported desktop management related technical policies and procedures; helped to create and maintain related documentation.
- Administered and assisted in deploying LANDesk 8.8 & 9 environments and Symantec Endpoint Protection for a client base of 3000+ machines.
- Deployed regularly scheduled and out of band security/OS patches and updates via LANDesk and other mechanisms.
- Co-developed an asset management system to track physical assets via barcode scanning devices.

System Support Analyst, July 2009 – September 2010

- Actively monitored an extensive production environment for washingtonpost.com and other high-traffic Post properties
- Acted as a liaison between coworkers and the development and infrastructure technology teams
- Provisioned, integrated, diagnosed, and maintained PC and Macintosh clients in an Active Directory environment

University Health Services; University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

Technical Assistant, May 2007 – July 2009

- Provided technical support for medical center staff
- Maintained system security in Windows Server 2003-based, Active Directory environment, performed hardware repairs and replacements including drive imaging

The Massachusetts Daily Collegian, Amherst, MA

Web Editor, September 2006 - May 2008

- Provided IT/Technical support, acted as lead web developer, liaised to university IT department
- Administered web-based systems, managed operations and web staff
- Maintained and updated website during production, redesigned website